Ngũgĩ mss., ca. 1950s-2014 LMC 2905
Lilly Library
- II. Writings by Ngũgĩ
  - Essays
    - "My Black Dolls - The African Dilemma" - draft, handwritten, undated (Box 25)
    - "My East Africa: Dreams and Visions" (Box 25)
      - Annotated typescript, undated, July 10, 1989 (Box 25)
      - Accompanying material, undated (Box 25)
    - "My Role as a Writer" - draft, handwritten, undated (Box 25)
    - "The Neo - in the Post" - draft, handwritten, undated (Box 25)
    - "The New Villages - They are a Social Problem" (Box 25)
      - Draft - handwritten, (first page only), undated (Box 25)
      - Typescript, undated (Box 25)
    - "The Novel and African Culture" (Box 25)
      - Draft - handwritten, undated (Box 25)
      - Draft - annotated typescript, undated (Box 25)
    - "Nuruddin Farah: A Statement of Nomination" - draft, typescript, undated (Box 25)
    - "Resistance to Repression" (Box 25)
      - Draft - handwritten with inset typescript, undated (Box 25)
      - Photocopy of draft, undated (Box 25)
    - "Return to the Roots: Language and History as the Two Sources for a Kenyan National Literature" (Box 25)
      - Outline - handwritten, undated (Box 25)
      - Draft - handwritten, undated (Box 25)
      - Draft - handwritten, undated (Box 25)
    - "Shakespeare in Africa" - handwritten, undated (Box 25)
    - "Statement on Vietnam" - handwritten, October 18, 1966 (Box 25)
    - "Struggle Over National Theatre" - handwritten, undated (Box 25)
    - "Submerged Languages: Submerged Peoples" (Box 25)
      - Draft - handwritten, undated (Box 25)
      - Annotated typescript, undated (Box 25)
      - Typescript, undated (Box 25)
    - "Thoughts Toward a National Language Policy" - draft, handwritten, undated (Box 25)
    - "To an African Student: A Challenge" - draft, handwritten, undated (Box 25)
    - "To Whom it May Concern: Re: The Moi-Kanu Regime's Continuing Danger to the Lives of Dissidents" - typescript, May 7, 1993 (Box 25)
    - "Toward a National Culture" - typescripts, undated (Box 25)
    - "Tribalism, Culture, and National Liberation" (Box 25)
      - Draft - handwritten, undated (Box 25)
      - Draft - handwritten, undated (Box 25)
    - "The Western and Me" - annotated typescript, August 31, 1967 (Box 25)
    - "What's My Color, What's My Race?" (Box 25)
      - Draft - handwritten, (2 pages), undated (Box 25)
      - Draft - annotated typescript, (3 pages), undated (Box 25)
      - Typescripts, undated (Box 25)
    - "Wole Soyinka and the Satiric Voice" - typescripts, undated (Box 25)
    - "The Writer and His Past" (Box 25)
      - Draft - handwritten, undated (Box 25)
      - Typescript, undated (Box 25)
    - "The Writer and His World" - draft, undated (Box 25)
      - Draft - handwritten, undated (Box 25)
      - Draft - handwritten, undated (Box 25)
    - "The Writer in a Changing Society" - draft, undated (Box 25)
    - "Writers in Politics" (Box 25)
      - Draft - handwritten, undated (Box 25)
      - Draft - handwritten, undated (Box 25)
      - Draft - handwritten, undated (Box 25)
      - Draft - handwritten, undated (Box 25)
      - Draft - annotated typescript, October, 1975 (Box 25)
      - Japanese translation, January, 1980 (Box 25)
    - "Voices and Icons: The Neo-colonial in Emergent African Cinema" (Box 25)
      - Draft - annotated typescript, April 25, 1995 (Box 25)
      - Typescript, undated (Box 25)
  - Speeches/Talks/Lectures
    - "Literature and Society" - Conference of Kenya Teachers, Nairobi School, 1973 (Box 25)
    - "The Links That Bind Us" - Acceptance speech for the Lotus Prize in Literature at the 5th Afro-Asian Writers Conference, Khazakhstan, 1974 (Box 25)
    - "The Robber and the Robbed: Two Antagonistic Images in Afro-American Literature and Thought" - American Studies Regional Conference, Abidjan, July 26 - July 28, 1976 (Box 25)
      - Draft - handwritten (Box 25)
      - Annotated typescript (Box 25)
    - "Education for a National Culture" - Education in Zimbabwe: Past, Present, and Future, University of Zimbabwe, August 27, 1981 - September 7, 1981 (Box 25)
      - Draft - handwritten (Box 25)
      - Typescript (Box 25)
    - "Education for a National Culture in the Third World" - Osaka Women's University, November 18, 1981 (Box 25)
      - Photocopy of annotated typescript (Box 25)
      - Typescript, 1981 (Box 25)
    - "Language and Literature" - International Book Fair, Harare, August 23-27, 1983 (Box 25)
    - " The Language of African Fiction" - Sir Douglas Robb Lectures, 1984 (Box 25)
    - The First Walter Rodney Memorial Lecture, 1985 (Box 25)
    - "Fight for Peace: Fight Racism", 1985 (Box 25)
    - "Kirira Na thiomi Cia Aabirika" - Belgium, October 26, 1986 (Box 25)
    - "Resistance to Damnation: The Role of Artists, Writers, and intellectual Workers in the Struggle for the Survival and Development of Children in the Frontline States and Southern Africa", Harare, March 1-5, 1988 (Box 25)
    - Symposium on Post - Colonial Kenya, September 9, 1990 (Box 25)
    - "Removing the Mountains on Our Back: The Struggle for Revolutionary Democracy in Kenya and Africa", Australia, September 29, 1990 (Box 25)
    - "Prospects for Democracy in Kenya" - Institute of Human Rights, Oslo Norway, September 21, 1991 (Box 25)
    - "Fire From the Mountains" - NYU Graduate of Arts & Sciences speech, New York (Box 25)
    - Hendrix College, April 14-16, 1994 (Box 25)
    - "Modern Ireland in the African Literary Imagination" - Post-Colonial Conditions: Ireland in a Comparative Context, December 5-6, 1997 (Box 26)
    - "Voices of Silence" - Albright College commencement speech, May 22, 1994 (Box 26)
    - "Literature and Politics: Transcending Borders" - Tenth Krishna Memorial Lecture, Miranda House, University of Delhi, February 19, 1996 (Box 26)
    - University Of Hawai'i at Manoa, October 7-9, 1997 (Box 26)
    - "Universities and the Magic Fountain: African Literature into the 21st Century" - Eric Ashby Lecture, 1999 (Box 26)
    - "Encounters with Censorship" - Symposium on Censorship keynote address, September 15, 2000 (Box 26)
    - "Waiting for the Italian" - Nonino Literary Prize acceptence speech, January 27, 2001 (Box 26)
    - Nazareth College, February 15, 2001 (Box 26)
    - Language, Culture & Politics: Africa into the 21st Century" - Southern Connecticut State University, April 19, 2001 (Box 26)
    - "Writers in Exile" - The International Festival of Art and Conflict: Writers in Exile, Yale, June 29, 2001 (Box 26)
    - "Out of Africa: Language, Knowledge and Empowerment" - MLA conference, New Orleans, December 28, 2001 (Box 26)
    - "Liberating Our Consciousness: South Africa in the Black Imagination" - Fourth Steve Bilko Annual Lecture, Cape Town, South Africa, September 12, 2003 (Box 26)
    - "Dis-Membering Practices: Planting European Memory in Africa" McMillan-Stewart Lectures, Harvard, March 14-16, 2006 (Box 26)
    - "Translation as a Bridge across Cultural and Political Divides" - Plenary lecture at UCI conference: Walls in Our Heads: Political Division and Cultural Imaginaries, October 2009 (Box 26)
    - "Celebrating Heroes and Sheroes" - Keynote speech on celebration of Kenya's Mashujaa Day, October 23, 2010 (Box 26)
    - "Africa and the World: Contemporary resistance and the New World Order", undated (Box 26)
    - "Aliens, Volunteers, and Experts", undated (Box 26)
    - "Finding Our Way in the World: Language, Knowledge and Sustaining One African Community", undated (Box 26)
    - "Ladies and gentlemen of the press", Denmark, undated (Box 26)
    - "Language and the Struggle for Democracy in Africa", undated (Box 26)
    - "Languages in Conversation: The Role of Translation in the Making of a Global Community", undated (Box 26)
    - "Literature and the Philosophy of our Education", undated (Box 26)
    - "Moving the Center", undated (Box 26)
    - "Moving the Center: Decolonizing Languages and Scholarship", undated (Box 26)
    - "Native Languages and the Politics of Decolonization", undated (Box 26)
    - Petals of Blood Launching Speech, undated (Box 26)
    - "Somalia and Pan-Africanism", undated (Box 26)
    - "The Struggle for Democracy in Africa", undated (Box 26)
    - "The Tension Between National and Imperialist Culture", undated (Box 26)
    - "The Writer and His Past", undated (Box 26)
    - Unidentified, undated (Box 26)
    - Flyers/Programs (Box 26)
  - Unidentified (2 folders) (Box 11)
- III. Writings by Others
  - About Ngũgĩ
    - Biographical materials (2 folders) (Box 26)
    - "As Seen From the Roots/ Part 1: Ngũgĩ wa Thiongo" - biographical television script, undated (Box 26)
    - Report on the Probe Committee Probing into the University's Stand Concerning the Ngũgĩ wa Thiong'o Issue (Box 26)
    - Library subject search (Box 26)
    - Abdelkrim (?) - "Petal's of Blood, Story, Narrative, Discourse" (Box 26)
    - A.M. Oppong-Affi - "African Religious Heritage in Achebe, Amadi & Ngũgĩ" (Box 26)
    - Africa News - "Ngũgĩ's Kenya", January 30, 1978 (Box 26)
    - Björkman, Ingrid - "Maitu Njugira by Ngũgĩ wa Thiongo - Intended and Real Effects" (Box 26)
    - Cancel, Robert (Box 26)
      - "Literary Criticism as Social Pilippic and Personal Exorcism: Ngũgĩ wa Thiongo's Critical Writings" (Box 26)
      - "Nadine Gordimer meets Ngũgĩ wa Thiongo: Text into Film in "Oral History" (Box 26)
    - Chakava, Henry - "Publishing Ngũgĩ: The Challenge, the Risk and the Reward" (Box 26)
    - Chesaina, Jane C. - "Who is on Trial in The Trial of Dedan Kimathi?" (Box 26)
    - Duodu, Kwabena M. - "Ngũgĩ and the Mau Mau: History as Literature" (Box 26)
    - Evans, Jennifer - "Mother Africa and the Heroic Whore: Female images on Petals of Blood" (Box 26)
    - Gacjukia, E.W. - "James Ngũgĩ and the Mau Mau War" (Box 26)
    - Gikanda, Simon - "Traveling Theory: Ngũgĩ's Return to English" (Research in African Literatures Vol.31, No. 2 Summer 2000) (Box 26)
    - Gitau, B.k. - "Ngũgĩ wa Thiongo - The African Paulo Freire?" (Box 26)
    - Godwin, Janet Elizabeth - "Messianic Manifestations: Revolution and Social Change in the Novels of Ngũgĩ wa Thiongo" (Box 26)
    - Goodwin, Ken - "'National Chauvinism Must Burn!': Utopian Visions in Petals of Blood and Matigari" (Box 26)
    - Gugelberger, George M. - "Blake, Neruda, Ngũgĩ wa Thiongo: Issues in Third World Literature" (Box 26)
    - Houemavo, Jacques-Marie Charles - "Ngũgĩ wa Thiongo's Evolution from A Grain of Wheat to Petal's of Blood" (Box 26)
    - Ikeddeh, Ime - "Ngũgĩ wa Thiongo: The Novelist as Historian" (Box 26)
    - Irumba, Dr. Katebalirwe-Amooti wa - "Class Suicide: Ngũgĩ wa Thiongo in Interviews and Discussions" - Anthology (Box 26)
    - Julien, Eileen (Box 26)
      - "Heroism in A Grain of Wheat" (Box 26)
      - "The Ideals of Ngũgĩ's Revolution. Part One: The Polemics" (Box 26)
    - Kamenju, Grant - "Petals of Blood as a Mirror for African Revolution" (Box 26)
    - Lindfors, Bernth - "Ngũgĩ wa Thiongo's Early Journalism" (Box 26)
    - Malik, Nasor - "Cultural Identity, Alienation and Resistance in the Work of Ngũgĩ wa Thiongo" (Box 27)
    - Masilela, Ntongela - "Ngũgĩ wa Thiongo's Petals of Blood" (Box 27)
    - Mazuri, Ali A. - "The Detention of Ngũgĩ wa Thiongo: A Report on a Private Mission" (Box 27)
    - MacCann, Donnaraee and Yulisa Amadu - "Escape or Rebel? The Case for Anti-Colonialist Education in Weep Not, Child " (Box 27)
    - McLaren, Joseph (Box 27)
      - "Critical Responses to Ngũgĩ wa Thiongo's Petals of Blood and Decolonizing the Mind" (Box 27)
      - "Thematic Continuity and Relevance in the Writings of Ngũgĩ wa Thiongo" (Box 27)
    - Mirii, Ngũgĩ wa - "Ngũgĩ wa Thiongo's The River Between for 'O' Level" (Box 27)
    - Miyamato, Masaoki (Box 27)
      - "The Detention of Ngũgĩ wa Thiongo - Truth and it's Background" (Box 27)
      - "The Possibility of African Literature" (Box 27)
      - "A Tentative Essay on Ngũgĩ wa Thiongo" (Box 27)
    - Morgan, Ed - "Spiritual and Political Rebirth in the Writing of Ngũgĩ wa Thiongo" (Box 27)
    - Ogude, James A. - "Ngũgĩ's Concept of History and the Post-Colonial Discourses in Kenya" (Box 27)
    - Osei-Nyame Jr., Kwando - "Ngũgĩ wa Thiongo's Matigari and the Politics of Decolonization" (Box 27)
    - Party Press, Reviews and Biblio - "Ngũgĩ's Mission 'for Those Who are Oppressed and Struggling'", 1983 (Box 27)
    - Pass, Ndeke Mokasa wa - "The Struggle Against Oppression as Depicted in Ngũgĩ wa Thiongo and Micere Githae Mugo's The Trial of Dedan Kimathi" (Box 27)
    - Reeves, Geoffrey W. - "Ngũgĩ wa Thiongo and Cultural Revolution in Kenya" (Box 27)
    - Reiss, Timothy J. - "Wizardry", article from Comp Lit News, NYU, May 2002 (Box 27)
    - Rauch, Erika - "An Analysis of the Central Male-Female Relationships in The River Between and Mission to Kala" (Box 27)
    - Seymour, Hilary - "Pedagogical Politics in Ngũgĩ wa Thiong'o's Petals of Blood" (Box 27)
    - Sharma, Govind Narain (Box 27)
      - "Ngũgĩ's Apocalypse: Marxism, Christianity, and African Utopianism in Petals of Blood" (Box 27)
      - "Ngũgĩ's Christian Vision: Theme and pattern in A Grain of Wheat" (Box 27)
    - Vaubel, Natasha C. - "From Fanon to Ngũgĩ: Notions of Violence and Communities in Struggle", 1990 (Box 27)
    - Waruingi, Gacheche - "Historical Realism in Ngũgĩ wa Thiongo's Early Novels" (Box 27)
    - YagombaIn, Obuonde - "Defense of Professor Ngũgĩ", August 21,1981 (Box 27)
    - Unknown (Box 27)
      - "How Far Can One Take Ngũgĩ as an Historical Commentator?" (Box 27)
      - "Ngũgĩ, A Black Educator" (Box 27)
      - "Ngũgĩ wa Thiongo - A Look into Literary World of Africa" (Box 27)
      - "The Writer in Politics: Ngũgĩ wa Thiongo's Petals of Blood" (Box 27)
  - Adaptations
    - Petal's of Blood - Mary Benson (2 folders) (Box 27)
    - An Adaptation of Ngũgĩ wa Thiongo's Novel Devil on the Cross - R.J. Ewu (Box 27)
    - Betrayals - screenplay based on A Grain of Wheat - Lawrence Jehu Kiiru (Box 27)
    - Kingdom of Earthly Wiles - dramatic adaptation of Devil on the Cross - Elizabeth Uzo Osisioma (Box 27)
  - Manuscripts
    - Balseiro, Isabel - Anthology of New South African Fiction (Box 27)
    - Cantalupo, Charles - A Literary Leviathan: Thomas Hobbes's Masterpiece of Language (Box 27)
    - Gethoi, Mutu wa - Elders of the Mace: To Wrestle with Damathia (Box 27)
    - Hale, Adelaide - Unidentified (Box 27)
    - Kibwana, Kivutha - Seasons of Sowing (2 folders) (Box 27)
    - Koinange, Jeff M. (Box 27)
    - Koinange-wa-Mbiyu: Mau Mau's Misunderstood Leader - revised proofs (Box 27)
    - Koumandareas, Menis - The Smell of Their Hair Makes Me Cry (Box 27)
    - Martens, Ludo - A Woman in the Congo (Box 27)
    - Momplaisir, Franchesca M. - Letter from Lelianne - novel draft (2 folders) (Box 27)
    - Mpofu, Stephen - Before They Die (Box 28)
    - Myambo, Melissa Tandwe - Jacaranda Journals (2 folders) (Box 28)
    - Ng'ang'a, Mukara - The People Shall Speak: A Novel from Detention (Box 28)
    - Ngũgĩ, Mukoma wa - Conversing with Africa (2 folders) (Box 28)
    - Njogu, Kimani - Dialogic Poetry: Contestation and Social Change in East African Verse Genres (Box 28)
    - Reiss, Timothy J. - Mirages of the Selfe [Chapter Seventeen. Descartes, Collective Tradition and Personal Agency (Box 28)
    - Searle, Chris - Words Unchained: Language and Revolution in Grenada (Box 28)
    - Tuma - Hama - African Absurdities (Politically Incorrect Articles) (Box 28)
    - Wango, Baines Njenga - The Founding and Growth of African Politics in Kenya 1900 - 1963 (2 folders) (Box 28)
    - Wanjau, Gakaara wa - Hingo ya Paawa - The Time of 'Power (Box 28)
    - Wanyeki, S. - God Loves the Rich (Box 28)
    - Winks, Christopher (Box 28)
      - Symbolic Cities in Caribbean Literature: Chapter III Containing the Ancestral House (Box 28)
      - Symbolic Cities in Caribbean Literature: Chapter IV Two, Three, How Many Havanas (Box 28)
    - Unknown (Box 28)
      - Smoke, Fire, and Liquid Blues: Eyewitness (Box 28)
      - Makori and Nyansiaboka (Box 28)
      - Muthoni and Waiyango (An Ogre) (and other short stories) (Box 29)
      - One for All (prison manuscript) (Box 29)
        - Handwritten manuscript (Box 29)
        - Typescript manuscript (Box 29)
      - Their Bones Were Ground into Powder (Box 29)
      - Marxism and African Literature, edited by Georg M. Gugelberger - proof, 1985 (Box 74)
  - Plays
    - Abour, Ojwando C. - 4: Strength from The Odyssey of Valour, adapted from White Highlands no More (Box 29)
    - Baraka, Amiri - Boy and Tarzan Appear in a Clearing, 1980 (Box 29)
    - Asige, David S. - Mr. Youthwing of Abiba, 1993 (Box 29)
    - Barot, Rahul (Box 29)
    - Chinweizu - The Divorce of Lawino and Ochol, 2000 (Box 29)
    - Derry Frontline and the Bogside Sculptors - Inside Out (Box 29)
    - Derry Frontline: Culture & Education - Death and the Maiden (Box 29)
    - Katiyo, Wilson - Magodo (Box 29)
    - Kihanya, Wanjiku wa - What Tribe is God (Box 29)
    - McKee, Ruth - State of Emergency, 1988 (Box 29)
    - Muchendu, P.N. - My Father's Sweat (Box 29)
    - Mulwa, David - The Little Drum (Box 29)
    - Munyoki, Salim - The Unfolding of a Trial (Box 29)
    - Olma, Eton Eish - So Long as the Race Shall Live (In Fourteen Movements) (Box 29)
    - Omari, Emman - Our Colorful Past (Box 29)
    - Rama, Dickson N.B. - Phantom (Box 29)
    - Ruganda - My Father the Glutton (Box 29)
    - Theatre Against Oppression - Intervene! (Box 29)
    - Uka, Kalu - Stonewalls (Box 29)
    - Wachira, Waigwa (Box 29)
      - From a Grain of Wheat (Box 29)
      - A Place in the Sun (Box 29)
      - Soledad Brother (Box 29)
    - Wanjau, Gakaara J. - Anti-Mau Mau Play Reke Acirithio Ni Mehia Make (Box 29)
    - Wanjiku? - Kigera the Destitute (Box 29)
    - Wandiri, T.J. & E.W. Alwora - Baruti (Box 29)
    - Zirimu, E.N. - The Hunchback" (Box 29)
    - Unknown (Box 29)
      - The Moving Finger (Box 29)
      - A People United (Box 29)
      - Othello (Box 29)
    - Unidentified ( 2 folders) (Box 29)
  - Poetry
    - Braithwaite, Kamau - "Barbajan Poems, 1492-1992" (Box 29)
    - Chi-ha, Kim (Box 29)
      - "Five Bandits", 1970 (Box 29)
      - "Cry of the People", 1974 (Box 29)
    - Chiri, Ruwa (Box 29)
    - Cipris, Zeljiko - The Transnationale and the Internationale (Box 29)
    - Hogan, Patrick Colm - The Death of the Goddess: A Poem in Twelve Cantos (Box 29)
    - The Death of the Goddess: A Poem in Twelve Cantos (Box 29)
    - Momplaisir, Francesca M. - "In My Mother's House" (Box 29)
    - Winyumiririe Mwagana? (Box 29)
    - Lashambi Ndungu (Box 29)
    - Theophilus Ojewale (Box 29)
    - Okoampa-Ahoofe Jr., Kwame (Box 29)
      - Canaveral Concerto and Other Poems (Box 29)
      - Revolution of Beggars, 1991 New Poems (Box 29)
    - p'Bitek, Okot (Box 29)
      - Song of a Prisoner - Draft, chapter 6 (Box 29)
      - Song of Lawino & Song of Ocol (incomplete) (Box 29)
    - William E. Street (Box 29)
    - Tanesu, G.Y. - "Of Spades and Ethiopians" (2 folders) (Box 30)
    - Yvonne? (Box 30)
    - Unknown/Unidentified (Box 30)
      - Prey to Emotion (Box 30)
      - The Name is Shade (Box 30)
      - Unidentified (3 folders) (Box 30)
  - Scholarly Papers
    - Achebe, Chinua - The African Writer and the Biafran Cause, 1968 (Box 30)
    - Adagala, Kavetsa - Language and Literature in Primary Schools (Box 30)
    - Adam, Hussein M. (Box 30)
      - Clan Conflicts and Democratization in Somalia (Box 30)
      - Comparing and Contrasting Selected Aspects of Eritrea and Somaliland (Box 30)
      - Frantz Fanon as a Democratic Theorist (Box 30)
      - Frantz Fanon: His Understanding (Box 30)
      - The Revolutionary Development of the Somali Language (Box 30)
      - Somali Irredentism Reconsidered (Box 30)
      - Somalia: A Terrible Beauty Being Born? (Box 30)
      - Somalia: Militarism, Warlordism or Democracy? (Box 30)
    - Africa Research & Publications Project Inc. - Working Papers, No. 1-4 (4 volumes) (Box 30)
    - Ahlberg, Beth Maina - "Women's Groups Networks: Their Concerns with Health Problems of Reproduction: A Case Study of Women's Groups" (Box 30)
    - Ahluwalia, Davinder Pal Singh - "Political Power, Political Opposition, and State Coercion: The Kenyan Case" (Box 30)
    - Alexander, Neville (Box 30)
      - Language Planning in South Africa with Special Reference to the Harmonization of the Varities og Nguni and Sotho (Box 30)
      - Language Planning in South Africa: Some Insights (Box 30)
    - Ali, Ahmed Q. (Box 30)
      - "A Critique of "Somalia a Nation in Turmoil" by Said S.S. Amatar" (Box 30)
      - "The Foreign Factor in the Somali Tragedy" (Box 30)
    - Amrov, Deborah P. - "Negotiating Meanings: Textiles and the Politics of Sexuality in the Swahili Society" (Box 30)
    - Anderson, Roger - Psychometrics, Sociolinguistics and Educational Selection (Box 30)
    - Ataöv, Prof. Dr. Türkkaya - The Philosophy of Zionism and its Implications in Africa (Box 30)
    - Ba, Amadou Hampate - The African Tale of Cinema (Box 30)
    - Banta, Thomas J. - James Baldwin's Discovery of Identity (Box 30)
    - Bantu, Susan Kagwiria - Africa's Responsibility for African Conflicts? (Box 30)
    - Barkan, Sandra - Emerging Definitions of African Literature (Box 30)
    - Beasnael, Sem Milantoloum - The Wrath and Commitment of African Writers (Box 30)
    - Bienefeld, Prof. Manfred (Box 30)
      - Global Development Trends in the Eighties: A Time of Growing Disparities (Box 30)
      - Karl Polanyl's 'Lessons of History' and the Present Crisis in the Developing World (Box 30)
    - Blyden, Edward - Black Aesthetics: The Aims and Methods for a Liberal Education for Africans (Box 30)
    - Boyd, Rosalind - Gender Issues and Popular Democracy in Contemporary Uganda (Box 30)
    - Chandan, Swarn - British Punjabi Literature: A Brief Introduction (Box 30)
    - Chennault, Stephen D. - Black Dialect: A Cultural Shock (Box 30)
    - Chick, John D. - Settler Attitudes to Mau Mau in the Novels of Robert Ruark (Box 30)
    - Settler Attitudes to Mau Mau in the Novels of Robert Ruark (Box 30)
    - Chien-jen, Chou - Lu Hsun: Pioneer of China's Cultural Revolution (Box 30)
    - Cowen, M.P. (Box 30)
      - Change in State Power, International Conditions and Peasant Producers: The Case of Kenya (Box 30)
      - Wattle Production in the Central Province: Capital and Household Commodity Production 1903-1964 (Box 30)
    - Currie, Katie (Box 30)
      - Recent Struggles in Kenya- The Significance of the Fall of Charles Njonjo (Box 30)
      - State and Class in Kenya-Notes on the Cohesion of the Ruling Class (Box 30)
    - Culhane, Garrett - A Literary Adventure: British Explorer Narratives of Africa (Box 30)
    - D'Costa, Jean - The West Indian Novelist and Language: A Search for a Literary Medium (Box 30)
    - DeGraff, Michel - Morphology in Creole Genesis: A Prolegomenon (Box 30)
    - Dipoko, Mbella Sonne - Cultural Diplomacy in African Writing (Box 30)
    - Durrani, Shiraz - Independence in Kenya and the Lost Opportunity to build a People Orientated Library Service (Box 30)
    - Edmondson, Locksley - "Black Power", Africa and The Caribbean (Box 30)
    - Eno, Omar A. - The Untold Apartheid Imposed on the Bantu/Jarer People in Somalia (Box 30)
    - Dr. Fagerberg-Diallo - Searching for Signs of Success: Enlarging the Concept of Education to Include Senegalese Languages (Box 30)
    - Gakuru, O.N. - Pre-Primary Education in Kenya (Box 30)
    - Gatabaki, Samuel M. - Monopolies, Restrictive Practices and Industrial Development (Box 30)
    - Gathitu, Kariuki - Kamukunji: The Kenyan Tiananmen Square (Box 30)
    - Gecau, Kimani - Interpretation of Literature in Society (Box 30)
    - Gilliam, Angela - Waigani Seminar Presentation (Box 30)
    - Gititi, Gitah - Narrative and National Formation: Comparative issues in Contemporary Africa and Latin American Literature (2 folders) (Box 30)